Guide to the Adolph Knopf Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Adolph Knopf papers
1916-1942
1916-1919
MS 1253
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3.75
(3 boxes)
The major part of the papers consists of reports and maps on the holdings of the Rochester Mines Company in Humboldt County, Nevada (1916-1917). During this period Knopf was on the staff of the U.S. Geological Survey. Also a small amount of professional correspondence and lecture notes, chiefly relating to his career as a professor of geology at Yale University. Eleven of the letters are from Charles Schuchert, a colleague in the department.
Knopf, Adolph, 1882-1966
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Adolph Knopf (1882-1966): on staff of U.S. Geological Survey from 1906-1945; professor of geology at Yale University, 1920-1951; professor emeritus from 1951; author of various books and articles.
Scope and Contents
The major part of the papers consists of reports and maps on the holdings of the Rochester Mines Company in Humboldt County, Nevada (1916-1917). During this period Knopf was on the staff of the U.S. Geological Survey. Also a small amount of professional correspondence and lecture notes, chiefly relating to his career as a professor of geology at Yale University. Eleven of the letters are from Charles Schuchert, a colleague in the department.
Mines and mineral resources -- Nevada; Educators; Geologists; Knopf, Adolph, 1882-1966; Schuchert, Charles, 1858-1942; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. Department of Geology and Geophysics
- Inventory
  Scope and Contents
  The Adolph Knopf Papers are mostly records of a group of silver mines in Nevada. Knopf's own connection with these is not clear, though a few of the materials seem to bear his annotations. The correspondence consists of letters to and from Charles Schuchert, one carbon copy of a letter to N. L. Bowen, donated by Mrs. Adolph Knopf in May 1972; and copies of correspondence with the Calaveras County Department of Mines and Mining, San Andreas, California, received from the Calaveras Heritage Council in May 1977. The donor of the rest of the material is unknown.
  - Correspondence, 1919-1942 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Reports, one with photographs, 1916-1917, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Maps, blueprints, drawings, 1916-1917, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, 1917, 1919, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Silver ore sample from the Rochester Mines Co., Nevada, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Additional Material, Accession 2000-M-131
  - Typescript of lecture notes for Adolph Knopf's course, Petrology and Petrography [prepared by B. Moneymaker], [1933] (Box 1)
- Additional material, 1939; Accession 2016-M-085
  This accession contains a bound copy of class notes on petrology, which was taught by Adolph Knopf at Yale University in 1939.
  - Bound copy of class notes on petrology, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)